Survival is key
Escape from Pretoria is a drama, history, thriller
film directed by Francis Annan.
South Africa, 1978.
Tim Jenkin and Stephen Lee, two white political activists from the African National Congress imprisoned by
the apartheid regime, put a plan in motion to escape from the infamous Pretoria Prison.
Tim Jenkin, played by Daniel Radcliffe.
Stephen Lee, played by Daniel Webber.
Denis Goldberg, played by Ian Hart.
Leonard, played by Mark Leonard Winter.
Mongo, played by Nathan Page.
Schnepel, played by Grant Piro.
Escape from Pretoria is a 2020 prison film co-written and directed by Francis Annan, based on the real-life prison
escape by three political prisoners in South Africa in 1979, starring Daniel Radcliffe and Daniel Webber.
It is based on the 2003 book Inside Out: Escape from Pretoria
Prison by Tim Jenkin, one of the escapees.
An international co-production between Australia and the United Kingdom, the film was shot in Adelaide, South Australia, in early
2019, both on location in the city and suburbs and in the Glenside studios of the South Australian Film Corporation.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, 1970s, political
activism, apartheid, anc (african national congress).
The tone is emotional and intense.